RG 009:004, Connecticut vs. Massachusetts
Connecticut State Library
- Series 4. Reports, 1890-1930
  - Massachussetts State Department of Health First Annual Report, 1915; 1 book (Box 4)
  - State of Connecticut Quality of Merrimac River Water Progress Report No. 1-3, 1929 July 12-October 10 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - State of Connecticut Quality of Merrimac River Water Progress Report No. 4; Memorandum re. Coagulation Experiments, 1929 October 11-31 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Series 5. Engineering Studies, 1928-1930
  - Report to the State of Connecticut upon an Investigation of the Effect of Diversions from the Tributaries of the Connecticut River, 1928 March; 1 volume (Box 4)
  - State of Connecticut Reports, Comments, and Bibliography
    - Chapter III Stream Flow, 1930; 1 volume
    - Chapter IV Navigation, 1930; 1 volume
    - Chapter IVB Power, 1930; 1 volume (Box 5)
    - Chapter V Pollution, 1930; 1 volume
      - State of Connecticut Progress Reports of Connecticut River Stream Pollution Studies to Accompany Chapter V
        - Volume 1, Numbers 1 to 5, 1928 June 16-August 25; 1 volume
        - Volume 2, Numbers 6 to 8, 1928 August 26-December 24; 1 volume
        - Volume 3, Numbers 9 to 14, 1929 July 8-September 14; 1 volume
    - Chapter VI Fish Life, 1930; 1 volume
    - Chapter VIII Ground Water, 1930; 1 volume
    - Chapter IX Agriculture, 1930; 1 volume
    - Chapter X Water Needs - Boston, 1930; 1 volume
    - Chapter XI, Volume 1, Eastern Supplies, 1930; 1 volume
    - Chapter XI, Volume 2, Eastern Supplies, 1930; 1 volume (Box 6)
      - State of Connecticut Progress Reports of Merrimac River Stream Pollution Studies to Accompany Chapter XI
        - Numbers 1 to 4, 1929 July 12-October 31; 1 volume
- Series 6. Stenographic Notebooks, undated
  - Stenographic notebooks, undated (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
- Series 7. War Department Materials, 1922-1929
  - Brief filed with War Department, 1928 January (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Hearing in re diversion of the Ware and Swift Rivers from the Connecticut River, 1928 February 9 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Motion for leave to file - Motion to cite in Secretary of War and Chief of Engineers as parties respondent, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Navigation, circa 1922-1928 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - War Department Swift and Ware Rivers exhibits, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
- Series 8. Correspondence, 1922-1931
  - Correspondence, 1930-1931, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Attorney General, 1929-1931 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Bunn, C.W., Special Master, 1930-1931 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Commonwealth of Masachusetts Metropolitan District Water Supply Commission, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Frank H. and Philip H. Burt, Shorthand Reporters, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Highway Department, State of Connecticut, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Law Offices of Benedict M. Holden, 1930-1931 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - Morris Knowles, Incorporated, 1928-1930 (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
  - Correspondence - New Jersey, State of, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - The Sanitary District of Chicago, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence - State Water Commission, State of Connecticut, 1929-1930 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence - Storey, Throndike, Palmer & Dodge, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence - Supreme Court of the United States, 1930-1931 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence - testimony, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence - War Department, 1922, 1927-1928, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence - Warren, Garfield, Whiteside, and Lamson, 1930-1931 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Series 9. Subject Files, circa 1900-1932
  - Agriculture, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - An inquiry into the conditions relating to the water supply of the City of New York, circa 1900 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Answer, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Answer to the Defendant's Answer, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Available supplies in Eastern Massachusetts, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Bailey vs. Wolburn, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Board of Water Supply City of New York, 1928-1929 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Briefs, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Case law and precedent, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Case, Lockwood & Brainard Co., Printers and Bookbinders, 1929-1932 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Case notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 11-14)
  - Chamber of Commerce of the United States, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Chas. T. Main, Inc., Engineers, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - State of Colorado vs. State of Kansas, et al., 1927 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Compacts, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Complaint, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Complaint - drafts, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Conclusions, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Conference - Bond Hotel, Hartford, Connecticut, 1928 June 7 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Connecticut River, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Connecticut River Pollution Studies and Survey of Sludge Deposits, circa 1930 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Damage, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Delaware River Diversion, Beach Pollution, and Boundary Cases Report, 1929 June 21 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Delegated powers of the United States, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Exceptions, undated (Box 7, Folder 28-29)
  - Exceptions to Report of Special Master - layout, circa 1930 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Experts, undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Fish life, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Hillsborough Mills vs. The City of Fitchburg, Brief for the Plaintiff, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Indexes and headings, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Jurisdiction, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Lawrence, Massachusetts water supply, 1930, undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Legal documents, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Legislation, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Massachusetts defense, undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Massachusetts project, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Memorandum on the State of Connecticut vs. the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Merrimac River, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 7, Folder 43-44)
  - Miscellaneous - draft legal documents, undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Miscellaneous - figures and tables, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Miscellaneous - legal cases and citations, undated (Box 7, Folder 47-48)
  - Missing typewriter, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Navigation, undated (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Necessity, undated (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Pleadings, undated (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Pollution, undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Population capacity, undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Power, undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Present conditions of the river at the Connecticut - Massachusetts state line, undated (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Reply to Defendant's Answer as amended, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Reserved powers of the states, undated (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Rights of sovereignty, undated (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Riparian rights, undated (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Special Master, undated (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Statement of fact, undated (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Statement of the case, undated (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Supporting documents, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Swift River, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - War Department, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Water Policy of the State of Connecticut, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Water resource investigations, circa 1928 January (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Series 10. Legislative Files, 1908-1929
  - Bill files - Commonwealth of Massachusetts, circa 1911-1927 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Bill files - Commonwealth of Massachusetts, reports, 1908-1924 (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
  - Bill files - Connecticut, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Bill files - federal, circa 1927-1929 (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
  - Bill files - miscellaneous, 1929, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Series 11. Press Files, 1926-1930
  - Clippings, 1926-1930, undated (Box 8, Folder 13-18)
  - Miscellaneous - articles, circa 1929, undated (Box 8, Folder 19-20)
- Series 12. Printed Documents, 1919-1931
  - Baldwin Tool Works, et al. vs. Fred. O. Blue, State Tax Commissioner, et al., undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Brief of Massachusetts Upon Complainant's Exceptions to the Report of the Special Master, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Commonwealth of Massachusetts, The Decennial Census, circa 1925 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Complainant's Brief for Hon. Charles W. Bunn, Special Master; Comments on Exhibits Filed With Plaintiff's Brief; Complainant's Digest of Evidence, circa 1929, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Draft - Brief for the Complainant in Support of (1) Motion to Strike Out Defendant's Answer (2) Motion to Strike Out Part of Defendant's Answer, undated (Box 8, Folder 25-26)
  - Joint Summary of Evidence, 1930 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Motion for Leave to File Bill in Equity Bill of Complaint, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 28-29)
  - Motion for Leave to File - Complainant's Exceptions to the Report of the Special Master, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Motion for Leave to File - Motion to Cite in Secretary of War and Chief of Engineers as Parties Respondent, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Motion for Leave to File Motion to Dismiss Defendant's Answer; Motion to Dismiss Defendant's Answer, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Motion for Leave to File - Motion to Strike Out Certain Part's of Defendant's Answer, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Motion to Strike Out Defendant's Answer; Motion to Strike Out Part of the Defendant's Answer, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Oral Argument, 1931 January 5 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Oral Argument before Hon. Charles W. Bunn, Master at St. Paul, Minnesota, circa 1930 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Revised Rules of the Supreme Court of the United States, circa 1925 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Underwood Typewriter Company vs. Frederick S. Chamberlain, Treasurer, Brief In Behalf of Defendant, circa 1919 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - United States Department of the Interior, The New England Flood of November, 1927, Geological Survey Water Supply Paper 636-C, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Wisconsin, et al. vs. Illinois, et al., 1925 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Wisconsin, et al. vs. Illinois, et al., Michigan vs. Illinois, et al., New York vs. Illinois, et al., 1929 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Series 13. Invoices, 1928-1931
  - Invoices A-R, 1928-1931 (Box 10, Folder 1-14)
  - Invoices S-Z, 1928-1931 (Box 11, Folder 1-5)
- Series 14. Maps, circa 1913-1930
  The series consists of maps and duplicates of maps that document the proposed water diversion from the Swift and Ware rivers which are tributaries of the Connecticut River.
  - Cities and Towns with Expected Demand on Metropolitan District Water Supply, based on Ex. D-13, circa 1930; 5 duplicate maps (Box 81)
  - General Plan of Water Supply in Eastern Massachusetts for Boston Metropolitan District, 1929 May; 1 map (Box 81)
  - General Plan of Water Supply in Eastern Massachusetts for Boston Metropolitan District, undated; 1 map (Box 81)
  - Map showing watercourses in Massachusetts and Connecticut and East-West drainage divide in central Massachusetts, undated; 7 duplicate maps (Box 81)
  - Present Development of Sudbury (unreadable) - Watersheds, based on exhibit D-1, undated; 1 map (Box 81)
  - Watershed of Connecticut River, 1928 February; 2 duplicate maps (Box 81)
  - The Commonwealth of Massachusetts. Map Showing Major Water Supplies of Massachusetts and Adjacent States Together with Sources Considered for the Future Use of the Metropolitan District. Prepared Under the Direction of the Joint Board Consisting of the Department of Health and the Metropolitan District Commission. Chapter 49, Resolves of 1919, 1922 January; 1 map (Box 13)
  - Hypothetical Stages of Retreat of the Glacial Margin in Ware and Quinsigamond Quadrangles, Massachusetts, United States Geological Survey, Bulletin 760, Plate VII, undated; 1 map (Box 13)
  - Map of the State of Connecticut to Accompany the Fourth Report of the State Sewage Commission, 1902; 1 map (Box 13)
  - State of Connecticut Map showing Route of High Tension Transmission Lines and Areas served by the Several Electrical Utilities. Prepared by the Public Utilities Commission, Revised to 1924 January 1; 1 map (Box 13)
  - Diagram Showing Actual Flow of Swift River and Depletion Thereof by Proposed Diversions with Low Water Stage at Hartford. Plotted for year 1924, 1929 February 28; 3 diagrams (Box 14)
    Included are two undated diagrams which depict flow figures from the various rivers and reservoirs in Massachusetts.
  - Gauge Heights of Connecticut River at Hartford, Connecticut, 1922 June-December; 1 map (Box 14)
  - United States Department of Interior, United States Geological Survey Topographic Maps, 1913-1927
    - Granby, Connecticut, 1925; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Guilford, Connecticut, 1913; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Saybrook, Connecticut, 1915; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Guilford, Connecticut, 1913; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Meriden, Connecticut, 1921; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Sandisfield, Massachusetts, 1915; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Hawley, Massachusetts, 1924; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Tolland, Connecticut, 1918; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Gilead, Connecticut, 1922; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Northampton, Massachusetts, 1925; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Belchertown, Massachusetts, 1923; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Greenfield Quadrangle, Massachusetts, 1923; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Palmer Quadrangle, Massachusetts, 1927; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Greylock, Massachusetts, 1925; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Warwick, Massachusetts, 1915; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Winchendon, Massachusetts, 1924; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Winchendon, Massachusetts, 1924; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Fitchburg, Massachusetts, 1927; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Marlboro, Massachusetts, 1914; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Groton, Massachusetts, 1923; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)
    - Saybrook, Connecticut, 1915; 1 sheet; 1:62,500 (Box 15)